BRANDON FANCHER

LEADER. BUILDER. WEB & MOBILE DEVELOPER.

CONTACT

- brandonfancher.com
- brandonfancher@gmail.com
- github.com/brandonfancher
- +1 (704) 778-1945
- Blacksburg, VA USA

EDUCATION

PROGRAMMING BLOCKCHAIN By Jimmy Song

January 2018

Completed Jimmy Song's in-person seminar on the mechanics behind Bitcoin and blockchain, covering topics such as elliptic curve cryptography, script and transaction parsing and signing, proof of work, and merkle proofs.

SPANISH / B.A.

Missouri Southern State University

Summa Cum Laude, 4.0 GPA 2009

Recognized as the Outstanding Student in Foreign Languages and completed an internship and certificate program in medical interpreting.

SUMMARY

I am a leader, manager and full-stack developer with a passion for building and delivering beautiful and compelling products and user experiences.

As Director of Mobile Engineering at Block.one, I currently lead a team of native iOS and Android engineers. As a developer myself, I work primarily with JavaScript, NodeJS, React and React Native targeting the web and mobile platforms.

Other Technologies: TypeScript, Jamstack, Gatsby, GraphQL/Apollo, REST, Redux, HTML/CSS/SCSS, Styled Components/Emotion, Swift, Blockchain, ECC, Agile & Scrum, Python (Flask, Django), Ruby (Rails, Sinatra), PostgreSQL and applicable ORMs, AWS (ElasticSearch, S3, Lambda) and more.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DIRECTOR & ENGINEERING MANAGER, MOBILE

Block.one | Blacksburg, VA | September 2019 - Present

Block.one is a producer of scalable, high-performance, open-source blockchain software and user-facing applications that build upon blockchain and smart contracts.

- Scaled the mobile team from two to 12 native iOS and Android developers spanning multiple projects.
- Proposed and architected, and organized development, delivery and documentation of multiple products, including blockchain authentication libraries, integrations with secure cryptographic signing hardware, and Swift and Java blockchain SDKs.
- Organized and led development of native iOS and Android apps for a new social network built on EOSIO blockchain technology.

BRANDON FANCHER

LEADER. BUILDER. WEB & MOBILE DEVELOPER.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (cont.)

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

Block.one | Blacksburg, VA | April 2018 - August 2019

Block.one is a producer of scalable, high-performance, open-source blockchain software and user-facing applications that build upon blockchain and smart contracts.

- Hired as a React web developer; I innovated and excelled.
- Continually assumed more responsibility; became de facto team lead for a small mobile team due to my prior mobile experience in React Native.
- Facilitated agile scrum ceremonies.
- Consistently promoted and defended the user experience.
- Spearheaded, architected and authored protocols, transports and specifications for inter-platform communication with our mobile applications.
- Architected and wrote platform-agnostic JavaScript libraries designed to be leveraged natively by iOS
 applications over JavaScriptCore.
- Became an internally recognized thought leader and influencer.

CONSULTANT & FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Levvel, LLC | Charlotte, NC | December 2015 - April 2018

Levvel helps clients transform their business with strategic consulting and technical execution services.

- Worked with clients from ideation to implementation.
- Collaborated with Levvel's Product Innovation and Design teams to create beautiful products tailored to our clients and their customers.
- Mentored junior developers and interns.
- Provided leadership and expertise in front-end technologies, including React and React Native.
- Regularly learned and mastered new technologies, frameworks and programming languages, rapidly.

PROJECT MANAGER, I18N & L10N

Choice Translating, Inc. | Charlotte, NC | June 2010 - December 2015

Choice Translating's services include translation, software and website localization, international brand validation, and interpreting services in over 200 languages.

- Automated processes, managed internationalization (i18n) and localization (I10n) projects.
- Oversaw production and delivery for global market research projects.

BRANDON FANCHER

LEADER. BUILDER. WEB & MOBILE DEVELOPER.

PROJECTS & COMMUNITY

LEAD DEVELOPER & BLOCKCHAIN ENGINEER

first_current | https://firstcurrent.com | August 2017 - April 2018

first_current is a working group of developers, designers, and product experts dedicated to making the world a better place by promoting the adoption of digital currencies.

- Designed and developed a proof-of-concept cryptocurrency wallet in React Native, complete with support for BIP32 hierarchical deterministic wallets and BIP39 mnemonic passcode backup/recovery.
- Currently developing an open-source web storefront in Node/Express and React with integrated Bitcoin and Bitcoin Cash payment support, and without intermediaries. This is in contrast to current solutions that redirect the user to an awkward invoice for payment and/or utilize centralized services that take a cut from the merchant.
- Developing small, open-source React components enabling easy front-end blockchain integrations.

LEAD DEVELOPER

Team Luna | https://teamluna.co | March 2016 - April 2018

Team Luna is a working group of developers, designers, and product experts committed to lifelong learning, advocating for developers, and fostering the local technology community in Charlotte.

- Developed an open-source iOS (React Native) transit app for the Charlotte community-Charlotte Light Rail.
- It is the most popular app for the Charlotte light rail and boasts over 2,000 monthly average users.
- Github: https://github.com/brandonfancher/charlotte-lightrail.

ORGANIZER & PRESENTER

Charlotte ReactJS Meetup | June 2016 - April 2018

Organize a well-attended monthly meetup focused on React and React Native.

FURTHER READING

For more information, visit https://brandonfancher.com.